Mama?
Well, the one that always comes to pick you up is your dad, right?
Daikichi isn't my dad.
Grandpa is my dad.
That's weird!
Everyone has a mom and dad.
So who's Daikichi anyway?
I don't know.
Rin-chan, you're always saying strange things like that.
Men can't have babies, right?
Shut up!
You don't need to have a dad!
Idiot!
Takes one to know one.
Idiot! Idiot! Idiot!
Hiro-sensei!
Let's go.
Kouki-kun called me an idiot!
He said it over and over.
Hiro-sensei!
Kouki-kun, do you live only with your mom?
My dad went off somewhere, and they got a divorce later.
What's a "divorce"?
It means to stop being married.
I wonder if my mom's not around because she got a divorce.
I wouldn't know.
They'll get mad at you if you don't wear your hat.
What?
The string is stretched out.
Rin-chan! Someone's here to pick you up!
Rin-chan!
It's Daikichi!
He's here to pick you up!
Rin-tan, pick up!
Maa-kun, it's okay.
Thank you.
See you later, Rin-chan.
Goodbye!
What do you want for dinner?
Let's see...
Kouki-kun! Your mom's here to pick you up!
Your mom is really pretty!
She's a noisy, old hag at home.
U-Um...
I hear Rin is always looking after Kouki.
I-Is that so?
My son can be a little rude, so he has trouble making friends.
Thank you very much.
No, not at all! I-In fact, I feel the same way!
Rin isn't the friendly type either.
I guess birds of a feather flock together.
Daikichi! You were saying something about me, weren't you?
It wasn't anything demeaning.
Come on, keep walking!
I don't want to have to carry you.
I won't ask you to!
Let's go!
Does Rin-chan prefer her dad?
I'm not her father.
I'm something like a relative.
I'm sorry! I just assumed...
Please, don't be!
Mom, you're slow!
I'm glad you made a friend.
Yeah!
Kouki-kun doesn't have a dad.
He went away somewhere after getting a divorce.
Rin, do you know what a divorce is?
Yeah. It's when you stop being married, right?
Yeah, something like that.
If God finds out, they'll be punished, won't they?
I wonder if my mom's not here because she got a divorce.
Do you want to meet her?
I don't know.
I see.
But...
If she's like Kouki-kun's mom, I might want to meet her!
Me too! Me too!
What was that?! Rin-chan's mom is...
Yeah. Grandpa's maid is probably Rin's mom.
That can't be!
Do you know anything about the maid?
Kawachi-san's farewell party
A farewell party? For me?
I'm sorry it took so long.
We've managed to settle down in time for winter orders.
Thanks,
but I can't stay out too late.
My girl's only six years old.
Don't tell me you haven't been out drinking even once since then?
Well, yeah. I shouldn't be doing that.
I don't even care about drinking and stuff anymore.
I guess I've aged.
You're still only 30.
And the workers in my department are pretty young,
but most of them have kids,
so we don't really go out to drink.
Right?
Yeah, you got that right.
I need to pick up my kid from nursery school.
I have two kids, and the younger one is three months old.
If I don't go home soon, my wife will...
She's a scary wife, isn't she?
It's really scary when she's angry.
Kawachi-kun!
Gotou-san.
I heard about the farewell party.
Yeah, but I can't go out at night, so...
But they went to all that trouble.
How about bringing your kid along?
I'll bring mine too!
Are you trying to say that you want to go drinking—
It'll be fine!
I'm looking forward to it!
Yes, yes, yes.
Daikichi, your phone.
Thanks.
Hello?
Daikichi? It seems Grandpa hired the maid from an agency—
Hold on a second.
So, do you know her name?
Yoshii Masako-san, spelled with the kanji for "correct" and "child."
That's the same way it's written on the mother-child health record, right?
I guess so.
Are you going to contact her?
She went and abandoned such a cute kid—
Calm down!
You saw the mother-child health record, right?
There's so much written in there,
and there's so much we still don't know!
Excuse me!
Like I said...
I can't even tell the difference between home and work anymore.
Sorry I'm late.
Oh, you're late! Here, have a seat.
Don't come any closer, you drunk!
Rin-chan?! You really came!
Thank you!
Oh, you're so cute!
Eat as much as you want, okay?
Here, have some.
Glad you could join us, Rin-chan!
Thank you!
Here, Rin-chan. Are you fine with orange juice?
Rin-chan is such a beauty!
She sure is!
She's blushing!
Yuu-kun, I'll scrape it together for you.
Thank you, Rin-chan!
Kawachi-san, have some more!
Rin might fall asleep on the way home, so...
Rin, I'm going to the lavatory for a bit.
Just call it "toilet"!
Yeah, yeah.
He basically threw us away.
If you're going to bail, you're basically doing a half-assed job.
Quitting while at your best...
Sales are gonna be tough from this month on.
Even if we manage to sell, management's going to compare sales to last year's.
I wonder what we should do.
What can a guy do?
The old me would've barged in and given them a piece of my mind.
I'm gonna leak.
Girls are so soft!
I want you as my kid!
My priorities have changed.
Kawachi-san.
About your transfer...
After seeing Rin-chan, I finally understand.
Right?
Mama! Mama!
I want to hold you forever!
Pick me up too!
Gotou-san, it looks like Rin-chan doesn't like it!
Masako-san...
What did you think about your child... about Rin?
Yuu-kun was so cute!
You sure like little kids, huh?
Yeah. There was a letter in the box.
Thanks.
It says there will be a meeting about elementary school admission.
I haven't done anything, and yet we get something like this.
What's wrong?
There's going to be an admission test and stuff, right?
There won't!
You can get in without any of that!
Really?
Really, really!
Compulsory education is awesome!
Drunkard.
Dammit! How about this?
Rin-chan, he's here!
E-Excuse me.
Jeez! Everyone else already left!
I'm sorry.
Kouki-kun, your mom's here!
I'm sorry, Kouki.
G-Good afternoon.
It's been a while.
Daikichi, are we going to make it?
I'll go call a taxi!
Thank you!
Tasu Elementary
Their ID cards will be turned around,
so their names won't be visible on the way back from school.
Also, advise your child not to go to the park alone
and not to go off with any person even if they know them.
This is hard.
Instead of teaching them to trust people,
we have to teach them to be suspicious.
That's true.
About that sheet we were given earlier...
Whoops.
Let me carry them for you!
How do you know what vaccinations were given until now?
S-Sorry.
Looks like I asked a weird question.
Not at all.
Do you have Rin-chan's maternity record book?
Yes, it's at home.
There's a page in there that lists vaccinations,
so it's okay.
I see.
I really don't know anything.
I only met Rin three months ago.
Only three months?
Yeah.
That's surprising.
I get the feeling that Rin-chan really trusts you.
You think so?
At home, she's always talking back and won't keep quiet.
That's proof that she trusts you.
You seem like family, no matter how you look at it.
Family...
R-Really?
Yes, really!
Is that so...?
What was that?
I jumped over your shadow!
I'm not tired.
It's okay.
Put me down!
Put me down, I say!
Thanks.
We're pretty much done.
A school bag?
Not yet.
That's no good!
The fashionable and brand name ones will be sold out soon!
A regular one is fine, isn't it?
That won't do for a girl!
Fine, I'll go this weekend.
Dai-chan, are you going to keep raising Rin-chan forever?
I heard you even transferred to another department.
I haven't thought that far ahead.
Mama!
I'll do yours next!
Okay!
You two sure get along well.
Well, yeah.
Moms and daughters are like friends.
Mom and Kazumi get along well too, now that I think about it.
It's not certain that Masako-san's circumstances are the same,
and maybe she wants to live with her daughter now.
She's had so many!
Her mother must have—
Souichi's Will
Da~pyon!
A will!
"Da~pyon"?
"If Masako were to find this, she would probably get rid of it,
so I've decided to do this the sifficult way.
However, I don't know how to write a secret code.
This ki-i-board thingy is making a fool out of me,
so my proress is very slow."
There are so many mistakes in his typing.
"This old man's enery has already run out,
hence, I'm giving up on blogging."
That was quick for a guy
in the "generation with perspective"!
The continuation is in Rin's health record.
Sorry, Rin.
I'm going to take a look.
I assume the person who finds this
really cares for Rin.
Hence, I shall give an account of Rin and her mother, Masako.
First of all, I would like to state that Masako is the type that is easily misunderstood
and is definitely not a bad person.
She says that she's a failure as a mother,
and that she feels sorry for Rin.
She still insists on keeping her position as my maid.
It'll probably stay that way in the future.
I believe that is the best for Rin's happiness.
Happiness? What does he mean?
Even if something should happen to me,
to keep any of my relatives from finding out about her,
she takes great pains to live a lifestyle that hides her existence.
Masako truly loves Rin as her mother.
However, she is still young,
so she might not have the maturity to act as a parent.
I don't get it,
but it looks like he truly cared about Rin and her mother.
Yoshii Masako
Daikichi!
W-What is it?
Hey, can you tie up my hair to make it look like rabbit ears?
Like Reina-chan's mom did once.
I can't!
Do it!
Definitely impossible! It's too much to ask!
Come on, do it!
Because...
They said I'm not cute.
Did someone say that to you?
Mii-chan said I'm not cute at all.
I think Rin is definitely cuter.
I want to be cute too.
All right.
She's already a young lady,
so she can get her feelings hurt.
Masako-san, did you know?
Rin has already matured a lot mentally.
Well, there's still a side to her that hasn't matured at all.
So an adult has to keep an eye on her.
Done!
This is...
♪ Twinkle, twinkle, little star. ♪
Hey, Rin.
♪ How I wonder what you— ♪
What are you doing?
I'm not supposed to tell anyone at home about Parents' Day.
Parents' Day?
So you're not allowed to look!
She's gonna do it with that hairstyle?
♪ Twinkle, twinkle, little star. ♪
♪ How I wonder what you are. ♪
Yoshii Masako
Did you leave Rin alone thinking that
she'd get over it soon enough since she didn't like you to begin with?
♪ Up above the world so high, ♪
♪ like a diamond in the sky. ♪
If that's true, I'll hate you with a passion.
I hope you at least had a good reason.
♪ Twinkle, twinkle, little star. ♪
But...
♪ How I wonder what you are. ♪
What reason could there be to abandon a child?
Study desk $600
Study chair $130
This one is cute!
It's cute, all right,
but you'll probably be using it for a while, so...
Oh, I know!
How about one that would suit a young lady?
A young lady?
You're right! Something that suits a young lady would be great!
Yeah!
You want to sit there again?
Do I look like a young lady?
Yeah, you could probably keep using this desk when you're in high school too.
Does "high school" mean you're all grown up?
I guess you'd be half an adult then.
I'm going to read, so listen.
A little girl went into a forest alone to play.
She got lost, and when she tried to find her way back,
she couldn't.
Suddenly, she came across a small house in the forest.
Is this Yoshii-san?
Yes.
$4
This one's cute, right?
Again? Rin!
Rin!
Hey!
Daikichi.
How many times do I have to tell you not to wander off?
Okay.
What's that?
Something to make me a young lady!
No way!
This is for much later!
Why?